bidvine.com 2019-05-09

# Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy - Bidvine

This is version 5 of the Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy, last updated on 2018-12-04.

#### 

Privacy Policy

This policy was last updated on December 4th, 2018.

 **Introduction**

We ask that you read this privacy policy for www.bidvine.com and any other websites through which Bidvine makes its online platform (Platform) available (collectively, the "Site") and as applications for mobile, tablet and other smart devices and application program interfaces (collectively, the "Application"), carefully as it contains important updated information on who we are, how and why we collect, store, use and share personal information and on how to contact us and supervisory authorities in the event you have a complaint.  

 **Who we are**

Bidvine Limited, 5 New Street Square, London, United Kingdom, EC4A 3TW, Company Registration Number 09242142, collects, uses and is responsible for certain personal information about you. When we do so we are regulated under the [General Data Protection Regulation](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN) which applies across the European Union (including in the United Kingdom) and we are responsible as ‘controller’ of that personal information for the purposes of those laws.

 **Use of Mobile Apps**

We also provide an App to access our Services or aspects of our Services: 

These Terms apply to the use of any App and the Service through the App. These Terms control over any Terms which may be imposed by either iOS or the Android platform and any other application distribution platform for use of the App and/or the Service through an App. 

Anywhere in the Terms where the word website is used shall also include the word App and vice versa. 

Your use of any App will terminate at the same time as use of the Services to which the App relates. 

 **The personal information we collect and use**

Information collected by us

In the course of providing the Platform and Site that enables various services to be provided by professionals (Professionals) who provide professional services (Services) and Customers who wish to purchase Services (Customers), we collect the following personal information when you provide it to us:

(i) _Master ID Data_ e.g. all Profile Content including names, appropriate images and videos, references, insurance information, and credentials, evidence of past work - of Customers and individual Professionals, postal addresses, electronic mail addresses, date of birth, telephone numbers, fax numbers, IP addresses, full-face photographic images, any other unique identifying number, characteristic, or code, messaging data (i.e. live and historical chat data), marketing data, and data collected through referral programmes or similar initiatives.  

(ii) _Usage Data_ (automatically collected information) e.g. meta-data, device data, log data, geographic/regional location, tracking and web analytics, cookies.

(iii) _Transactional Data_ e.g. Bid data, invoices, any transactional records. Information collected from other sources.

(iv) _Medical/Health Data_ e.g. limited information you choose to disclose about past injuries or health conditions relevant to services you are requesting (i.e. personal training).

We also obtain personal information from other sources as follows:

We use Master ID Data that identify natural persons from third-party web-services, including [clearbit](https://clearbit.com/), company websites and social media identities to enhance Profile Content on the Site.

Profile Content will be enhanced as follows:

  * Improved individual description
  * Addition of social media and website URLs not entered upon registration 
  * Addition of media not uploaded, but available on websites/social media identities 

 **Unregistered Professionals’ Profile Content Publishing**

We may use publicly available non-proprietary data from which natural persons can be identified to create a directory, and associated profiles, of professional service providers that have yet to register on the Site. The unregistered professionals associated with the profiles we create can choose to claim their profile and make any modifications to the profile content we publish as they deem necessary. Similarly, unregistered professionals can request the deletion of their profile by emailing support@bidvine.com. Unregistered professionals will be required to verify their association with the professional listing.

 **How we use your personal information**

We use your personal information as follows:

  * Master ID Data - _send you information we think you may find useful or which you have requested from us, including information about our products and services [or those of carefully selected third parties], provided you have indicated that you do not object to being contacted for these purposes; and allow, with your consent, carefully selected third parties to send you information directly which you may find useful regarding their products and services. Master ID Data is also used to help verify your identity and to facilitate users interacting with one another (i.e. submitting requests, sending bids, exchanging messages, etc.)_
  * Usage Data - _audit the downloading of data from the Site; improve the layout and/or content of the pages of the Site and Application and customise them for users; identify visitors to the Site; and carry out research on our users' demographics and tracking of sales data; we may disclose anonymised aggregate statistics about visitors to and users of the Site in order to describe our services to prospective partners and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes._
  * Transactional Data - _enable us to process your orders for credits and to provide you with the services and information offered through the Site and Application and which you request; administer your account with us; and verify and carry out financial transactions in relation to payments you make online.  _
  * Medical/Health Data - _enables us to provide service professionals with relevant information specific to some customer service requests (i.e. a personal trainer will need to be informed of pre-existing inquiries or heart conditions)._

 **Use of Customer information by Professionals**

If you are a Customer, Professionals may use a Customer Management Tool provided by Bidvine to help them organise information regarding bids involving you and other customers. Where a Professional uses this tool to organise information about you, we act on their behalf as a ‘data processor’ of that additional information. The Professional, not us, is the ‘data controller’ of this additional information.

If you have any questions regarding how any Professional uses your data, you should contact the Professional. If you wish to exercise any of the rights in the ‘Your Rights’ section of this Policy (below), we will respond to you in our capacity as data controller - that is, in respect of our operation of Bidvine generally. If you wish to exercise your rights in respect of any Professional’s use of your data - in their use of the Customer Management Tool or otherwise - you should contact the Professional.

 **Who we share your personal information with**

We routinely share Master ID Data; Usage Data; Medical/Health Data and Transactional Data with our employees, agents or affiliates to operate our services for you, including: parties that provide products or services to us or on our behalf and parties that collaborate with us in the provision of products or services to you. In some instances, such parties may also provide certain information technology and data processing services to us so that we may operate our business. As a result, your personal information may be accessed in Canada, India and in the Philippines, and in some cases, other countries. We require that employees, agents or affiliates enter into the requisite contractual agreements which require that they comply with this Privacy Policy and the requisite European Data Protection Laws.

We will share personal information with law enforcement or other authorities if required by applicable law. We will not share your personal information with any other third party.

 **Bidvine User Checks**

The provision of Master ID Data is required from you to enable us to carry out some basic id checks. The degree of checks depend on whether you are a professional or customer user. We will inform you at the point of collecting information from you, whether you are required to provide the information to us. We may check your Personal Data against any particulars on any database (public or otherwise) or through any third party identity verification service. If the information you have provided us does not allow us to verify your identity then you may not be able to register an account with us. 

 **How long your personal information will be kept**

We will hold a copy of your Master ID Data; Usage Data; Medical/Health Data and Transactional Data for the contract law statutory limitation period to help prevent fraud and to comply with statutory law for retaining information such as UK tax law (currently 6 years). Your data will be removed from our systems six years from the termination of the account or request for erasure or following a one-year period of inactivity.

 **Reasons we can collect and use your personal information**

  * We rely on consent as the lawful basis on which we collect and use your Master ID Data.
  * We rely on consent as the lawful basis on which we collect and use Usage Data.
  * We rely on consent as the lawful basis on which we collect your Health/Medical data.
  * We rely on processing being necessary for the performance of the Service related contracts as the lawful basis for processing Transactional Data.

 **Consequences of our use of your personal information**

  * We will disclose your Personal Data to any of our affiliates, or to our agents or contractors who assist us in providing the services we offer through the Site, processing transactions, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in other tasks, from time to time. Our agents and contractors will only use your information to the extent necessary to perform their functions. 
  * In the event that we undergo re-organisation or are sold to a third party, you agree that any Personal Data we hold about you may be transferred to that re-organised entity or third party. 
  * We may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or if we believe that such action is necessary to prevent fraud or cyber crime or to protect the Site, or the rights, property or personal safety of any person. 

 **Public forums**

The Site may, from time to time, make chat rooms, message boards, newsgroups and/or other public forums available to its users. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when using these and never disclose your personal information. 

 **Your rights**

Under the [General Data Protection Regulation](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN), you have a number of important rights free of charge. In summary, those include rights to:

  * fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your use personal information
  * access to your personal information and to certain other supplementary information that this Privacy Policy is already designed to address
  * require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold
  * require the erasure of personal information concerning you in certain situations
  * receive the personal information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to a third party in certain situations
  * object at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for direct marketing
  * object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you
  * object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information
  * otherwise restrict our processing of your personal information in certain circumstances

For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, see the [Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals rights under the General Data Protection Regulation.](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/)

If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:

  * Email us at support@bidvine.com from the email address associated with your Bidvine account. Alternatively, you can call us at +44 20 3322 9594 and answer specific questions to verify your identity.
  * let us know the information to which your request relates

If you would like to unsubscribe from any email newsletter you can also click on the ‘unsubscribe’ button at the bottom of the email newsletter. It may take up to 7 days for this to take place.

 **Privacy of Children**

Only persons 18 years of age or older may use the Platform. If we discover that an individual under 18 has provided us with personal information, we will close the account and delete the associated personal information. We may where permitted by law, retain certain information internally for purposes described in this Policy.

 **Automated Decision-Making**

Our Site does not employ any kind of automated decision making or profiling in any of the offered features which would have any legal effect or would otherwise have any significant effect on a natural person.

 **Keeping your personal information secure**

Bidvine is committed to protecting the security of your Information and takes reasonable precautions to protect it. We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, or used or accessed in an unauthorised way. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.

Internet data transmissions, whether wired or wireless, cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and as a result, we cannot ensure the security of Information you transmit to us, including personal information and user content; accordingly, you acknowledge that you do so at your own risk. If you want detailed information from [Get](https://www.getsafeonline.org/)[ Safe Online ](https://www.getsafeonline.org/)on how to protect your information and your computers and devices against fraud, identity theft, viruses and many other online problems, please visit [www.getsafeonline.org](http://www.getsafeonline.org/). Get Safe Online is supported by HM Government and leading businesses.

We use industry-standard encryption to protect your data in transit. This is commonly referred to as transport layer security (“TLS”) or secure socket layer (“SSL”) technology.

Once we receive your data, we protect it on our servers using a combination of technical, physical, and logical security safeguards. The security of the data stored locally in any of our Software installed on your computing device requires that you make use of the security features of your device. We recommend that you take the appropriate steps to secure all computing devices that you use in connection with our Site, Software, and Services. 

If Bidvine learns of a security system breach, we may attempt to notify you and provide information on protective steps, if available, through the email address that you have provided to us or by posting a notice on the Site.

 **External links**

The Site may, from time to time, contain links to external sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or the content of such sites.

 **Payment processing**

Payment details you provide will be encrypted using secure sockets layer (SSL) technology before they are submitted to us over the internet. 

Credit card payments made on the Site are made through our payment gateway provider, Stripe. You will be providing credit or debit card information directly to Stripe which operates a secure server to process payment details, encrypting your credit/debit card information and authorising payment. Information which you supply to Stripe is not within our control and is subject to Stripe’s own privacy policy and terms and conditions. 

Paypal payments made on the Site are made through our payment gateway provider, Braintree. You will be providing credit or debit card information directly to Braintree which operates a secure server to process payment details, encrypting your credit/debit card information and authorising payment. Information which you supply to Braintree is not within our control and is subject to Braintree's own privacy policy and terms and conditions. 

Payments made on the iOS Application are made through Apple. You will be providing credit or debit card information directly to Apple which operates a secure server to process payment details, encrypting your credit/debit card information and authorising payment. Information which you supply to Apple is not within our control and is subject to Apple's own privacy policy and terms and conditions. Which can be found [here](https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/uk/terms.html). 

Payments made on the Android Application are made through Google. You will be providing credit or debit card information directly to Google which operates a secure server to process payment details, encrypting your credit/debit card information and authorising payment. Information which you supply to Google is not within our control and is subject to Google's own privacy policy and terms and conditions. 

 **Security**

We place great importance on the security of all personally identifiable information associated with our users. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information under our control. For example, our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorised personnel have access to personal information. Whilst we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of information will never occur, we use all reasonable efforts to prevent it. 

You should bear in mind that submission of information over the internet is never entirely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of information you submit via the Site whilst it is in transit over the internet and any such submission is at your own risk. 

It is advisable to close your browser when you have finished your user session to help ensure others do not access your personal information if you use a shared computer or a computer in a public place. 

 **Storage of your information**

Information that you submit via the Site and Application is sent to and stored on secure servers located in the European Union. This is necessary in order to process the information. Information submitted by you may be transferred by us to our other offices and/or to the third parties mentioned in the circumstances described above (see Information sharing), which may be situated outside the European Economic Area (EEA) and may be processed by staff operating outside the EEA. The countries concerned may not have similar data protection laws to the EEA. Where we transfer your information we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected. By submitting information via the Site, you agree to this storing, processing and/or transfer. 

 **How to complain**

We hope that we can resolve any query or concern you raise about our use of your information.

[The General Data Protection Regulation](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN) also gives you right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the European Union (or European Economic Area) state where you work, normally live or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred. You may contact the UK supervisory authority the [Information Commissioner ](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/)who may also be contacted by telephone: [0303 123 1113].

 **Changes to this privacy policy**

We may change this privacy policy from time to time when we make a major change we will inform you via email. We may also post minor changes to this Policy, along with their effective date, at a well-articulated part of the Site. Please note that your continued use of Bidvine after any change means that you agree with, and consent to be bound by the changes. If you disagree with any changes in this Policy please discontinue use of the Site.

 **How to contact us**

Please contact us if you have any questions about this privacy notice or the information we hold about you.

If you wish to contact us, please send an email to support@bidvine.com, write to 52-54 High Holborn, London, UK, WC1V 6RL, or call us on 02033229594 between the hours of 9 am to 6 pm, Monday to Friday

#### 

Cookie Policy

This policy was last updated on December 4th, 2018.

 **Cookies on this website**

We use cookies and other data intelligence and analysis technologies on this website for various purposes. In most cases, we will need your consent in order to use cookies on this website. The exception is where the cookie is essential in order for us to provide you with a service you have requested (eg to enable you to purchase credits).

Cookies are small pieces of information which are issued to your device when you visit a website or application and which store and sometimes track information about your use of the Site. A number of cookies we use last only for the duration of your session and expire when you close your browser. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to the Site and will last for longer. 

There is a notice on all our web pages which describes how we use cookies and which also provides a link to our website privacy policy. If you use this website after this notification has been displayed to you, we will assume that you consent to our use of cookies for the purposes described in this website cookie policy and our website privacy policy.

 **Third-party cookies**

We work with third party suppliers who may also set cookies on our website, for example Google Adwords Remarketing, which we use for advertising purposes. These third-party suppliers are responsible for the cookies they set on our site. If you want further information please go to the website for the relevant third party. You will find additional information in the table below.

The main cookies and data analysis and behavioural intelligence technologies we use on the platform are: 

Cookie| Description  
---|---  
AdWords Conversion Tracking (Google)  
| Conversion tracking is a tool that shows us what happens after a user clicks on (Google) ads.  
Adwords Remarketing (Google)| Remarketing helps us reach people who have visited our website or used our app. Previous visitors or users can see ads as they browse websites that are part of the Google Display Network, or as they search for terms related to Bidvine's services on Google.  
Bing Ads| Conversion tracking is a tool that shows us what happens after a user clicks on Microsoft (Bing) and Yahoo ads.  
Booxscale  
| Booxscale is a third party advertiser which uses Bidvine content to advertise relevant information on third party websites. Booxscale tracks users when they land on a page and when they submit a request on Bidvine.  
Clearbit  
| Enables the capturing of additional user information (i.e. social media pages, avatar, etc.) in order to not display so many forms.  
Facebook Connect  
| Enables interaction between services. For example, the ability to use your Facebook credentials to login to Bidvine.  
Facebook Custom Audience| Facebook Custom Audience helps us reach people who have visited our website or used our app. Previous visitors or users can see ads as they browse Facebook and websites they are affiliated with.  
Google Tag Manager| Google Tag Manager is a tag management system created by Google to manage JavaScript and HTML tags used for tracking and analytics on websites.  
Hotjar| Hotjar is a tool that records videos of user sessions on the website. It displays mouse movements, clicks, scroll, and key press activity. In addition, it provides tools to request user feedback in the form of surveys.  
Intercom| Intercom is a customer service tool which enables Bidvine to respond to user inquiries. This tool shows us recent user activity to provide efficient customer service.  
Segment| A customer data platform connects data from across our properties (app and web) as well as get data to and from tools used across the organisation. This provides us with a better user profile allowing for improved analytics, personalisation, and marketing.  
  
Sentry| A tool for tracking errors that happen on the website.  
Trustpilot| Trustpilot is a third-party review site where users share their experience using Bidvine.  
  
Universal Analytics (Google)| This web analytics cookie collects information about how visitors use the Websites, which website the user came from, the number of each user's visits and how long a user stays on the Websites.  
Woopra| Woopra is a real-time customer analytics service used by sales, service and marketing teams. The platform is designed to help organizations optimize the customer life-cycle by delivering live, granular behavioural data for individual website visitors and customers.  
  
 **How we use cookies on our platform:  **

  * remember that you have visited us before; this means we can identify the number of unique visitors we receive. This allows us to make sure we have enough capacity for the number of users that we get; 
  * customise elements of the promotional layout and/or content of the pages of the Site; 
  * collect anonymous statistical information about how you use the Site (including how long you spend on the Site) and where you have come to the Site from, so that we can improve the Site and learn which parts of the Site are most popular with visitors; 
  * and gather information about the pages on the Site that you visit, and also other information about other websites that you visit, so as to place you in a "market segment". This information is only collected by reference to the IP address that you are using, but does include information about the county and city you are in, together with the name of your internet service provider. This information is then used to localise the service providers most suitable to you. For more information about this type of interest based advertising, and about how to turn this feature off please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/ ](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/)

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can change your browser to prevent that or to notify you each time a cookie is set. You can also learn more about cookies by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browser. Please note, however, that by blocking or deleting cookies used on the Site, you may not be able to take full advantage of the Site. 

In addition to cookies, tracking Gifs may be set by us or third parties in respect of your use of the Site. Tracking Gifs are small image files within the content of the Site or the body of our newsletters so we or third parties can understand which parts of the Site are visited and whether particular content is of interest.
